<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Specifications on FOL</title>
    <link>https://follang.org/docs/spec/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Specifications on FOL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;{year}, FOL</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 10:08:56 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://follang.org/docs/spec/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Modules</title>
        <link>https://follang.org/docs/spec/modules/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://follang.org/docs/spec/modules/</guid>
        <description>Imoprting modules System libraries This is how including other libraries works, for example include fmt module from standard library:
use fmt: mod[std] = {fmt}; def main: mod[init] = { fmt::log.warn(&amp;quot;Last warning!...&amp;quot;) } To use only the log namespace of fmt module:
use log mod[std] = {fmt::log}; def main: mod[init] = { pro[] main: int = { log.warn(&amp;quot;Last warning!...&amp;quot;) } } But let&amp;rsquo;s say you only wanna use ONLY the warn functionality of log namespace from fmt module:</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Behaviour</title>
        <link>https://follang.org/docs/spec/behaviour/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://follang.org/docs/spec/behaviour/</guid>
        <description>Build-in functions Fol has some build-in functions offered by compiler, and you access them by . (with space/newline/bracket before):
var contPoint: ptr[int] = 10;	// make a pointer and asign the memory to value of 10 .print(.pointer_value(contPoint));	// print the dereferenced value of pointer Macro system are a very complicated system, and yet can be used as simply as in-place replacement. A lot of build-in macros exist in the language to make the code more easy to type.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Control</title>
        <link>https://follang.org/docs/spec/control/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://follang.org/docs/spec/control/</guid>
        <description>Statements and expressions </description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Types</title>
        <link>https://follang.org/docs/spec/types/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://follang.org/docs/spec/types/</guid>
        <description>Every value in Fol is of a certain data type, which tells Fol what kind of data is being specified so it knows how to work with that data. There are four main subsets: simple, container, complex and special.
Simple Simple types are the most primitive type of data:
int[options], flt[options], chr[options], bol Intiger type An integer is a number without a fractional component. We used one integer of the u32 type, the type declaration indicates that the value it’s associated with should be an unsigned integer (signed integer types start with i, instead of u) that takes up 32 bits of space:</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Operators</title>
        <link>https://follang.org/docs/spec/operators/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://follang.org/docs/spec/operators/</guid>
        <description></description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Variables</title>
        <link>https://follang.org/docs/spec/variables/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://follang.org/docs/spec/variables/</guid>
        <description>Here are some of the ways that variables can be defined:
var[pub,mut] somename: num[i32] = 98; var[pub,exp] snotherone: str = &amp;quot;this is a string&amp;quot; var[~] yetanother = 192.56 var[+] shortlet = true var anarray: arr[str,3] = { &amp;quot;one&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;two&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;three&amp;quot; } var asequence : seq[num[i8]] = { 20, 25, 45, 68, 73,98 } var multiholder: set[num, str] = { 12, &amp;quot;word&amp;quot; } var anothermulti: set[str, seq[num[f32]]] = { &amp;quot;string&amp;quot;, {5.5, 4.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Ownership</title>
        <link>https://follang.org/docs/spec/pointers/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://follang.org/docs/spec/pointers/</guid>
        <description>Stack vs Heap The Stack What is the stack? It&amp;rsquo;s a special region of your computer&amp;rsquo;s memory that stores temporary variables created by each function (including the main() function). The stack is a &amp;ldquo;LIFO&amp;rdquo; (last in, first out) data structure, that is managed and optimized by the CPU quite closely. Every time a function declares a new variable, it is &amp;ldquo;pushed&amp;rdquo; onto the stack. Then every time a function exits, all of the variables pushed onto the stack by that function, are freed (that is to say, they are deleted).</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Functions</title>
        <link>https://follang.org/docs/spec/functions/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://follang.org/docs/spec/functions/</guid>
        <description>A subprogram definition describes the interface to and the actions of the subprogram abstraction. A subprogram call is the explicit request that a specific subprogram be executed. A subprogram is said to be active if, after having been called, it has begun execution but has not yet completed that execution.A subprogram declaration consists of an identifier, zero or more argument parameters, a return value type and a block of code.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Errors</title>
        <link>https://follang.org/docs/spec/errors/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://follang.org/docs/spec/errors/</guid>
        <description>Unlike other programming languages, FOL does not have exceptions (Rust neither). It has only two types of errors:
 braking errors recoverable errors  Breaking errors cause a program to fail abruptly. A program cannot revert to its normal state if an unrecoverable error occurs. It cannot retry the failed operation or undo the error. An example of an unrecoverable error is trying to access a location beyond the end of an array.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Pipes</title>
        <link>https://follang.org/docs/spec/pipes/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://follang.org/docs/spec/pipes/</guid>
        <description>Piping is a process that connects the output of the expression to the left to the input of the expression of the right. You can think of it as a dedicated program that takes care of copying everything that one expressionm prints, and feeding it to the next expression. The idea is the same as bash pipes. For example, an subprogram output is piped to a conditional through pipe symbol | then the conditional takes the input and returns true or false.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Concurrency</title>
        <link>https://follang.org/docs/spec/concurrency/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://follang.org/docs/spec/concurrency/</guid>
        <description>Concurrency is the ability of different tasks of a program to be executed out-of-order or in partial order, without affecting the final outcome. This allows for parallel execution of the concurrent tasks, which can significantly improve overall speed of the execution in multi-processor and multi-core systems. In more technical terms, concurrency refers to the decomposability property of a program into order-independent or partially-ordered tasks.
There are two distinct categories of concurrent task control.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Objects</title>
        <link>https://follang.org/docs/spec/objects/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://follang.org/docs/spec/objects/</guid>
        <description>A type declaration binds an identifier, the type name, to a type. Type declarations come in two forms:
 alias declarations and type definitions (objects): records, enums, units and classes.  Alias declaration An alias declaration binds an identifier to the given type. All the properties of the type are bound to the alias too: credit to golang:
typ[pub] I5: arr[int, 5]; So now the in the code, instead of writing arr[int, 5] we could use I5:</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Generics</title>
        <link>https://follang.org/docs/spec/generics/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://follang.org/docs/spec/generics/</guid>
        <description>Generic functions - lifting The generic programming process focuses on finding commonality among similar implementations of the same algorithm, then providing suitable abstractions so that a single, generic algorithm can cover many concrete implementations. This process, called lifting, is repeated until the generic algorithm has reached a suitable level of abstraction, where it provides maximal reusability while still yielding efficient, concrete implementations. The abstractions themselves are expressed as requirements on the parameters to the generic algorithm.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>