<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Syntactic sugar on FOL</title>
    <link>https://follang.org/docs/700_sugar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Syntactic sugar on FOL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;{year}, FOL</copyright>
    
        <atom:link href="https://follang.org/docs/700_sugar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Pipes</title>
        <link>https://follang.org/docs/700_sugar/pipes/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://follang.org/docs/700_sugar/pipes/</guid>
        <description>Piping is a process that connects the output of the expression to the left to the input of the expression of the right. You can think of it as a dedicated program that takes care of copying everything that one expressionm prints, and feeding it to the next expression. The idea is the same as bash pipes. For example, an subprogram output is piped to a conditional through pipe symbol | then the conditional takes the input and returns true or false.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mixture</title>
        <link>https://follang.org/docs/700_sugar/mixture/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://follang.org/docs/700_sugar/mixture/</guid>
        <description>Optional var someMixtureInt: ?int = 45; Never var someNverType: !int = panic(); </description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Limits</title>
        <link>https://follang.org/docs/700_sugar/limits/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://follang.org/docs/700_sugar/limits/</guid>
        <description>Limiting is a syntactic way to set boundaries for variables. The way FOL does is by using [] right after the type declaration type[], so: type[options][limits]
Initger limiting Example, making a intiger variable have only numbers from 0 to 255 that represents an RGB value for a single color:
var rgb: int[][.range(0..255)]; Character limiting It works with strings too, say we want a string that can should be of a particular form, for example an email:</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Rolling</title>
        <link>https://follang.org/docs/700_sugar/rolling/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://follang.org/docs/700_sugar/rolling/</guid>
        <description>Rolling or list comprehension is a syntactic construct available FOL for creating a list based on existing lists. It follows the form of the mathematical set-builder notation - set comprehension.
Rolling has the same syntactic components to represent generation of a list in order from an input list or iterator:
 A variable representing members of an input list. An input list (or iterator). An optional predicate expression. And an output expression producing members of the output list from members of the input iterable that satisfy the predicate.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>